All right, so let's talk about a couple of
other important quality management terms.
So one other term that
you need to be aware
of is something called
verified deliverables.
Verified deliverables is
something that you as a project
manager and your team
are going to be performing.
Basically, it's testing the product,
right?
Is the product meeting the requirements
and is it meeting the quality standards?
So basically, the two questions we're
asking is, are we?
we building the right product and are we
building it correctly?
So it's not just a case of
making sure you're meeting
the customer's requirements,
that's only one part.
But it's also making sure it's within the
appropriate standards, right?
You're building the
product according to the
appropriate quality
management standards, right?
So according to your own
standards, your organization
standards, your industry standards, right?
So ISO standards and Six Sigma standards
and so and so forth.
Again, just like when you're building a
house.
You don't just want to
put some bricks together
and some pieces of wood
together and build a house.
You need to make sure
everything is according
to code, according
to the latest standards.
So the electrical and the plumbing and so
and so forth.
It's making sure it's according to the
local building codes.
So the deliverables then, they're going to
be tested.
They're going to be checked to make sure
it's meeting the customer's requirements
and it's complying to the appropriate
standards and regulations.
Now, just a side note on this,
the team verifies the deliverables.
That's what verification is.
So verification refers to quality control.
So the team themselves are testing the
product.
That's known as quality control or the
process is control quality quality.
Whereas the customer is going to accept
the deliverable and that process is,
you know, as validate scope and that's one
of the processes that we talked about in
the scope management section right so the
customer is going to be validating right
is it meeting our requirements and then
they're the ones that are going to be
accepting and that process is known as
validate scope now another term a couple
of other terms that you just need to be
aware of again at a very very high level
are these two terms here attribute
sampling variable sampling right now these
are two terms, major terms
as part of six sigma, but you
don't need to worry about
them for the PMP exam as much.
You just need to know that these terms
exist more than anything else, right?
So attribute sampling, also known as
discrete data, variable sampling,
also known as continuous data.
So attribute sampling is always just a
past, fail scenario, yes, no, on-off type
of thing, whereas variable sampling refers
to the actual degree of conformity.
And in a variable sampling, you can do
some kind of mathematical computations.
So just a very simple example.
Think of a sports team.
In a sports team, you've got all these
different players and they're all playing
a particular position and they all have
numbers at the back of their jerseys.
You try adding up those numbers or doing
some mathematical computations on those
numbers that's at the back of their
jerseys.
Add them up, divide them, what do you get?
You get a completely meaningless value.
it doesn't mean anything.
So that would be attribute data.
Or rather that would be attribute
sampling.
Variable sampling on
the other hand, you could
actually do some kind of
mathematical computation.
You could get the average age
of the team, the average height,
average number of goals
scored, and so on and so forth.
Now, a couple of other important terms.
Important to understand how a distinguish
between precision and accuracy.
What does it mean to be precise versus
accurate?
Well, precision basically means data
points are clustered together,
they have very little
scatter, whereas accurate
is close to the mean
or it's right on the mean.
So the very simple example.
Best way to explain this, we have a target
board here.
You're firing shots at this target board
and they're all landing in one location.
All of these shots are landing here.
That would be precise.
or very little scatter, right?
They're all landing exactly equal distance
apart.
That would be precise.
Accuracy, one shot right in the centre,
that would be accurate.
So that's the difference between precision
and accuracy.
So these are just a couple of then or a
few additional quality management terms
that you should be aware of for the PMP
exam.